I just launched my robotic arm for
ロボティックアームを
the first time only to discover that it was swinging around loosely.
初めて動かすと規則性なく回転することが確認できた
I challenged you to figure out why and I gave you a hint.
皆さんにはその理由を考えていただき 私からはヒントを出します
Assuming that you're up for the challenge,
課題に取り組んでいただくにあたり
you might have seen the following warning line,
次の警告ラインを目にしたことと思います
"Controller Spawner couldn't find the expected controller manager ROS interface."
「Controller Spawner が目的のコントローラーマネージャー ROS インターフェースを見つけられません 」
I'm going to jump right to the punch line here.
この該当部分へ飛びます
It turns out that we were missing a runtime dependency.
ランタイム依存関係が欠如していることがわかります
ROS packages have two different types of dependencies;
ROS パッケージには ビルド依存と実行依存という
build dependencies, and run dependencies.
2 種類の依存関係があります
You fix the first build dependency by using a combination of
最初に Google サーチと apt-get の組み合わせを使用して
Google search and apt-get to install the ROS kinetic controller manager package.
ROS 動的コントローラーマネージャーパッケージをインストールし ビルド依存を修正します
Doing this allowed the package to build without complaints but when you
こうすることで パッケージが不具合なく構築できますが
ran it you got a warning and things didn't function as expected.
一方で実行すると警告が出て目的の機能が実行できません
This is where the rosdep tool comes in handy.
ここですぐに使える rosdep ツールを導入します
The rosdep tool will check for a packages missing dependencies,
rosdep ツールを使用すれば パッケージに欠如している依存関係をチェックし
download them and install them.
必要に応じてこれらの依存関係をダウンロードしてインストールすることができます
Let's go ahead and take a look at
では先へ進み simple_arm パッケージで欠如している
the dependencies that were missing from the simple_arm package.
依存関係を見てみましょう
Let's first go ahead and kill Gazebo and all of the running nodes.
先へ進み Gazebo とすべての実行ノードを削除します
You can do so by entering Ctrl C in the ROS Master console window.
Ctrl C を ROS マスターコンソールウィンドウで入力して実行できます
Now in the root of your catkin workspace with setup, ".Bash source."
ここで catkin ワークスペースのルート内で ".Bash source." を設定します
You're going to want to type the command "rosdep
コマンド "rosdep check,"
check," and then the name of your package.
と入力し そしてパッケージ名前を入力します
Here it's, "simple_arm," and then hit enter.
ここでは "simple_arm," と入力し [enter] を押します
And there you have it, a list of
さあ 出てきました
the system dependencies that are missing and where to get them.
欠如しているシステムの依存関係のリストとその入手先です
Now we could have just use apt-get to install these but I'm going to show you a trick.
ここで apt-get を使用してこれらをインストールしますが コツをお見せしましょう
You can simply let rosdep do it.
簡単に rosdep にインストールさせることができます
To make rosdep install packages,
rosdep でパッケージをインストールするには
invoke the following command from the root of the catkin workspace.
Catkin ワークスペースのルートで次のコマンドを呼び出します
Rosdep Install -I simple_arm, and then hit enter.
ここでは "Rosdep Install -I simple_arm" と入力し [enter] を押します
The script will then install the missing Debian packages and there you have it.
スクリプトは欠如している Debian パッケージにインストールされ このようになります
Now, when you launch the simple_arm package everything should be operating as expected.
simple_arm package を起動すると すべてのことが期待どおりに動作するはずです
The joint controller, now that it's actually on your system,
ジョイントコントローラーは 現在実際に皆さんにシステム上にあり
will be loaded and the arm will no longer swing around loosely. There we go.
これがロードされてアームはもうバラバラには回転しなくなりますご覧のとおりです
Gazebo has been launched and as you can see the arm is rigid.
Gazebo が起動し ご覧のとおりアームが固定されました
With all packages properly installed,
すべてのパッケージが正しくインストールされたところで
you will now learn more about ROS packages in
ROS パッケージについてさらに掘り下げて学習し
preparation for writing your own nodes in the next lesson.
次のレッスンで行うノード作成コマンドの記述に備えましょう